Chris Albanese | Front-End Developer

212.203.1091

Christopher@CafeRE.com

Orlando, FL

www.ChristopherAlbanese.com

LinkedIn: /in/christopheralbanesefl/

Professional Summary

Front-End Developer with a primary focus on JavaScript and React. Chris has extensive experience in business development, marketing and education, and brings a deep understanding of how quality software development can enrich the lives of users and exceed the goals of stakeholders.

Technical Skills

Front End: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Gatsby, Redux, JSX, jQuery, Swift, Markdown,

TypeScript, WordPress, Bootstrap, Emotion JS, D3JS, Canvas, Sass/SCSS

Back End: REST Api, Express, Mongo DB, Node JS, Mongoose, Firebase

Software: Git, GitHub, VSCode, Vim, Sketch, PhotoShop, Illustrator, Figma, macOS, Windows

Relevant Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PHOTODAY; ORLANDO, FL - DEC 2018-PRESENT

Develop and maintain business applications for photography studios and consumer facing e-commerce website. Follow agile methodologies to quickly engineer and iterate features while adhering to best practices to ensure code is readable, maintainable and easily refactored. I was instrumental in shipping a number of prominent features like Gallery List Virtualization, Drag and Drop Matching, Custom Theme Previews, Image Cropping and Virtual Preview of print products.

FREELANCE DEVELOPER, MOTILITY SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS; ORLANDO, FL - JUNE 2020

Created new product pages based on mockups from the design team. A WordPress project that integrated custom PHP pages using the client's existing design library to ensure new pages would seamlessly fit within the established brand identity.

MOBILE DEVELOPER, WWW.RECALCAPP.COM, ORLANDO, FL; JUNE 2017 - OCTOBER 2017

Developed an iOS app for Real Estate Professionals to assist with common math and date calculations. Built with Xcode using Swift 4, UIKit, CocoaPods and incorporates ads using AdMob from Google.

WEB DEVELOPER & OWNER, WWW.REALESTATEACADEMYOFORLANDO.COM; ORLANDO, FL; JUNE 2016 - PRESENT

Developed and maintain an eCommerce site for a real estate school built on WordPress using WooCommerce and incorporating payment gateways from Square and PayPal.

Education

University of Florida – Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration

University of South Florida - Associate of Arts